ticketweb.ca 2016-06-28

# TicketWeb - Privacy Policy

### TicketWeb Canada Privacy Policy

**Your Privacy Rights**  
_Last Updated: January 8, 2009_

Welcome to TicketWeb! TicketWeb respects the privacy of our customers. We have developed this Privacy Policy to demonstrate our commitment to protecting your privacy.  This Privacy Policy is intended to describe for you, as an individual who is a user of TicketWeb.ca and our services, the information we collect, how that information may be used, with whom it may be shared, and your choices about such uses and disclosures.  This Privacy Policy also applies to transactions made, and data gathered, by Ticketweb's telephone call centres in connection with selling tickets to Canada-based events (and associated goods and services).  All information you provide to our call centres will only be used and disclosed in accordance with this Privacy Policy.  This policy describes circumstances in which your use of TicketWeb.ca or our services constitutes your consent for the collection, use and disclosure of your information for the purposes described in this Privacy Policy, as well as other circumstances where your express consent will be obtained.  This Privacy Policy is directed towards consumers rather than businesses and is not intended to cover information about businesses or business purpose activities.

We encourage you to read this Privacy Policy carefully when using our website or services or transacting business with us.  By using our website, you are accepting the practices described in this Privacy Policy.  TicketWeb Canada is a subsidiary of Ticketmaster and is a part of the Ticketmaster family of businesses. For a complete list of all Ticketmaster businesses, visit[www.ticketmaster.com/h/about_us.html](http://www.ticketmaster.com/h/about_us.html).

TicketWeb Canada does not share your personal information with these businesses or other members of its corporate family unless you consent to us sharing this information for identified purposes.

If you have any questions about our privacy practices, please refer to the end of this Privacy Policy for information on how to contact us.

#### Consent

We only collect, use and/or disclose your personal information with your consent.  We will ask you for your express consent if you would like to receive offers and/or information from us and/or an event provider.  In addition, this Privacy Policy identifies various purposes for which personal information you provide us will be used, such as processing the transaction you requested, processing payment and preventing fraud.  By providing us with your personal information and engaging in a transaction with us, you implicitly consent to our collection and use of your personal information for these identified purposes.

#### Information we collect about you

**In General**. Information that we collect from you, either online or through our call centres, can generally be categorized as either anonymous or personally identifiable.  Anonymous information is information that is not identified with a specific individual, such as the type of browser being used and what web pages have been accessed. Personally identifiable information ("personal information") is information that you provide to us that is uniquely associated with you, such as your name, address, email address, telephone number, user name and passwords.  Unless we specifically tell you we are doing so, we do not associate the anonymous information we collect with your personal information.  When you provide personal information through our website, the information may be sent to servers located in Canada, the United States and other countries around the world.  Regardless of where your personal information may be kept, it will be protected by the safeguards described in this Policy.

**Personal information**. We may collect and store any personal information you enter on our website, provide through our call centres or otherwise provide to us in some other manner for the purposes described in this Privacy Policy. The information you provide includes identifying information, such as your name, address, e-mail address, and telephone number, and, if you transact business with us, financial information such as your payment method (valid credit card number, type, expiration date or other financial information).  You also may provide information about your interests and activities, your gender and age, and other demographic information.  We may also collect anonymous information about you which is described later in this policy.

#### How we use the information we collect

**In general**. By utilizing our ticketing services and providing us with your personal information, you consent to our collection and use of your personal information as follows:

  * to deliver the products and services that you have requested; 
  * manage your account and provide you with customer support; 
  * perform research and analysis about your use of, or interest in, our products, services, or content, or products, services or content offered by others;
  * display content and advertising tailored to your interests;
  * verify your eligibility and deliver prizes in connection with contests and sweepstakes you have participated in; enforce our terms and conditions;
  * manage our business and as otherwise described to you at the time of collection.

**Financial information**. We may use financial information or payment method to process payment for any purchases or sales made on our website or through our call centres, to enroll you in the discount, rebate, and other programs in which you elect to participate, to protect against or identify possible fraudulent transactions, and otherwise as may be reasonably needed to manage our business in connection with your transaction (for example, to identify you at the box office if you are picking up tickets, to facilitate refunds for cancelled events, for audit purposes, etc.).

**Job applicants**. If your personal information is submitted through our website when applying for a position with our company, the information will be used solely in connection with considering and acting upon your application.  We may retain your personal information for a period of time, but only for the purpose of considering your application for current or future available positions.  This information may be shared with third-party service providers (such as third party recruitment agencies) retained by us to collect, maintain and analyze candidate submissions for job postings.

#### Your choices about collection and use of your information

  * You can choose not to provide us with certain information, but that may result in you being unable to use certain features of our website because such information may be required in order for you to open a My TicketWeb account; purchase tickets, products or services; participate in a contest, promotion, survey, or sweepstakes; ask a question; or initiate other transactions on our website.
  * When you provide your email address on our website, you will be given a choice as to whether you want to receive e-mail messages about promotions or special offers from third parties to whom we send your information (such as event providers).  Once we have provided your information to an event provider or another third party with your consent, you will have to change your preferences regarding such communications directly with that third party.

#### With whom we share your information

We want you to understand when and with whom we may share personal or anonymous information we have collected about you or your activities on our web site or while using our services.

**Personal information**. We do not share your personal information with others except with your consent and in the following situations: _and_ in the following situations:

  * **Event providers**. We sell tickets on behalf of others; we do not produce or otherwise bring you events. The venues, promoters, artists' representatives and fan clubs, teams, leagues and others who are involved in, produce or bring you events are known as event providers.  When an event provider wishes to present an event, it provides TicketWeb with details about the event, including the quantities and prices of the tickets that the event provider desires to sell.  TicketWeb charges the customer's credit card for the ticket price and remits to the event provider the ticket price proceeds. In addition, when you buy tickets, you are acquiring tickets and services from, or using tickets and services provided by, the event providers.  TicketWeb communicates personal information to event providers using secure connections.  The event providers collect and use your information for the purposes of providing ticketing related services for you.  Event providers may use your information to issue a ticket, provide you with important event-related communications, such as a notice if there is a cancellation or change in the timing of the event, provide you with assistance if you lose your tickets and for other such ticketing related purposes.  Both TicketWeb and the event provider collect the information needed to provide you with these important notices and to address customer service problems, including at the venue's will call/box office window on the night of the event.  In addition, if you have provided your express consent during the purchase process, the event provider may contact you regarding future events and special offers.  Event providers are subject to applicable privacy legislation, which may include the Personal Information Protection and Electronic Documents Act, the Personal Information Protection Act of British Columbia and Alberta and Quebec's Act respecting the protection of personal information in the private sector.  The event providers are required to comply with their obligations under laws applicable to their operations, including privacy legislation. In addition, event providers may have their own privacy policies that govern their use of your personal information.  If you want to learn about a particular event provider's privacy policy, or if you do not want to receive any further communications from an event provider, or if you have other questions for an event provider, you should contact that event provider directly.
  * **Authorized service providers**. We may share your personal information with our authorized service providers that perform certain services on our behalf.  These services include fulfilling orders, processing credit card payments, delivering packages, providing customer service and marketing assistance, performing business and sales analysis, supporting our website functionality, and supporting contests, sweepstakes, surveys and other features offered through our website. These service providers may have access to personal information needed to perform their functions but are not permitted to share or use such information for any other purposes.  We require all of our service providers to comply with the safeguards described in this policy.
  * **Business partners**. With your consent, we may also share your personal information with businesses with which we partner to offer you products, services, promotions, contests and/or sweepstakes through our website or our services, such as discounted hotel stays or special dining offers.  If you are interested in these offers, the business partners will be identified to you at the time you purchase or decide to participate in an offer or program being offered through them.  When you elect to engage in a particular merchant's offer or program, you authorize us to provide your email address and other information relevant to the offer or program to that merchant.  These businesses may use your personal information in accordance with their own privacy policies. If you want to learn about a particular merchant's privacy policies, or you do not want to receive communications from a particular merchant, then you must contact that merchant directly. Your personal information is only provided to those businesses whose offers you elect to participate in and not to other businesses advertising on our website.
  * **Other Situations**. By using our services and providing us with your personal information, you consent to our disclosure of your personal information in the following circumstances: 
    * **In response to legal requirements** , including in response to a subpoena, a court order, or a request from law enforcement or other government agency; to establish or exercise our legal rights; and to defend against legal claims.
    * **As reasonably necessary to protect the rights, property or safety of our company, our users, or our employees** , including investigations or preventative actions regarding suspected illegal activity, suspected fraud or other wrongdoing, to enforce our website terms and conditions or other agreements or policies, and to protect TicketWeb and other visitors to the website or users of services or products provided by TicketWeb.
    * **In connection with a substantial corporate transaction** , such as the sale of our business, a divestiture, merger, consolidation, or asset sale, or in the unlikely event of bankruptcy.  Any third parties to whom we may disclose personal information may only use and disclose your personal information as described in this Privacy Policy unless you otherwise consent.

#### Third-party websites

There are a number of places on our website where you may click on a link to access other websites that do not operate under this Privacy Policy.  For example, if you click on an advertisement or a search result on our website, or if you click on a link giving you information about a particular event, you may be taken to a website that we do not control.  These third-party websites may independently solicit and collect information, including personal information, from you and, in some instances, provide us with information about your activities on those websites.  We recommend that you consult the privacy statements of all third-party websites you visit by clicking on the "privacy" link typically located at the bottom of the webpage you are visiting.

#### How you can access your information

If you have a My TicketWeb account, you have the ability to review and update your personal information online by logging into your account.  You can also review and update your personal information by contacting us.  More information about how to contact us is provided below.

If you have an online account with us, you also may choose to close your account at any time by contacting TicketWeb Canada customer service.  After you close your account, you will not be able to sign in to our website or access any of your personal information. However, you can open a new account at any time.

#### Retention Policy

If you close your My TicketWeb account, we may still retain certain information associated with your account for analytical purposes and recordkeeping integrity, as well as to prevent fraud, collect any fees owed, enforce our terms and conditions, take actions we deem necessary to protect the integrity of our web site or our users, or take other actions permitted by law.  In addition, if certain information has already been provided to event providers or to other third parties with your consent, the use and retention of that information will be subject to those third parties' policies.  TicketWeb has implemented a retention policy to prevent personal information from being retained for a period that is longer than reasonably necessary to deliver the products and/or services purchased using TicketWeb's services.

#### How we protect your personal information

We take appropriate security measures (including physical, electronic and procedural measures) to help safeguard your personal information from unauthorized access and disclosure.  For example, only authorized employees are permitted to access personal information, and they may do so only to the extent such access is required for permitted business functions.  We require our authorized service providers to protect your personal information in a similar fashion.  In addition, we use encryption in the transmission of your sensitive personal information between your system and ours, and we use firewalls to help prevent unauthorized persons from gaining access to your personal information.  We communicate your personal information to event providers and authorized service providers using secure connections.

Although we take appropriate security measures as required by law, no security is perfect. Users should always take care with how they handle and disclose their personal information and should avoid sending personal information through insecure email.  For information about how to protect your personal information, please refer to the resources from any of the following websites:

  * **Office of the Privacy Commissioner of Canada** (http://www.privcom.gc.ca/)
  * **Office of the Information and Privacy Commissioner of Alberta** (http://www.oipc.ab.ca/home/)
  * **Office of the Information and Privacy Commissioner of British Columbia** (http://www.oipc.bc.ca/sector_private/public_info/index.htm)
  * **Commission d'accès à l'information du Québec** (http://www.cai.gouv.qc.ca/index-en.html)

#### Children's privacy

Our website is a general audience site, and we do not knowingly collect personal information from children under the age of 13.

#### Where we store your information

This Privacy Policy is intended to cover collection of personal information from residents of Canada.  Please be aware that your information will be stored in servers located in Canada, the United States where our central database is operated, as well as elsewhere in the world.  Your information may be processed in any of these places.  The data protection and other laws of the United States and other countries might not be as comprehensive as those in Canada.  Please be assured that we take reasonable steps to ensure that your privacy is protected.  By using our services, you understand that your information may be transferred to our facilities and those third parties with whom we share it or otherwise disclose it as described in this privacy policy.

#### Other information collected using our website

**Use of cookies and other technologies to collect information**. We use various technologies to collect information from your computer and about your activities on our site.

  * **Information collected automatically**. We automatically collect information from your browser when you visit our website.  This information includes your IP address, browser type and language, access times, the content of any undeleted cookies that your browser previously accepted from us (see "Cookies" below), and the referring website address.
  * **Cookies**. Cookies. When you visit our website, we may assign your computer a "cookie" (a small, unique identifier text file) or series of cookies, to facilitate access to our site and to personalize your online experience.  For example, when you sign in to our website, we will record your email address provided and the name on your My TicketWeb account in the cookie file on your computer.  We also may record your password in this cookie file, if you indicated that you would like your password saved for automatic sign-in.  For security purposes, we will encrypt any usernames, passwords, and other user or member account-related data that we store in such cookies.  In the case of sites and services that do not use a user or member ID, the cookie will contain a unique identifier.  Through the use of a cookie, we also may automatically collect information about your online activity on our site, such as the web pages you visit, the links you click, and the searches you conduct on our site.  Most browsers automatically accept cookies, but you can usually modify your browser setting to decline cookies.  If you choose to decline cookies, please note that you may not be able to sign in or use some of the interactive features offered on our website.  The "Help" portion of the toolbar on most browsers will tell you how to prevent your browser from accepting new cookies, how to have the browser notify you when you receive a new cookie, or how to disable cookies altogether.
  * **Other Technologies**. We may use standard Internet technology, such as pixel tags, web beacons and other similar technologies, to track your use of our site.  We also may include web beacons in promotional e-mail messages or newsletters to determine whether messages have been opened and acted upon. A web beacon is a small file placed on a web page that allows a website to perform various tasks, including count users who have viewed that page or to access cookies. We also may receive an anonymous identification number if you come to our site from an online advertisement displayed on a third-party website.  The information we obtain in this manner enables us to customize the services we offer our website visitors to deliver targeted advertisements and to measure the overall effectiveness of our online advertising, or other activities.
  * **Information collected by third-party advertising companies**. We may allow third-party advertising companies, including ad networks, to display advertisements on our site.  These companies may use tracking technologies, such as cookies, to collect anonymous information about users who view or interact with their advertisements.  Our website does not provide any personal information to these third parties, but they may collect information about where you, or others who are using your computer, saw and/or clicked on the advertisements they deliver, and possibly associate this information with your subsequent visits to the advertised websites. They also may combine this information with personal information they collect from you. The collection and use of that information is subject to the third-party's privacy policy.  This information allows them to deliver targeted advertisements and gauge their effectiveness.  Some of these third-party advertising companies may be advertising networks that are members of the Network Advertising Initiative, which offers a single location to opt out of ad targeting from member companies([www.networkadvertising.org](http://www.networkadvertising.org/)).

**Anonymous and aggregated information.**. We may combine anonymous information and/or aggregate information we collect with additional anonymous information collected from other sources.  We may share anonymous information (including aggregate information) we collect regarding our users with third parties (such as advisors, advertisers and investors) and our affiliated Ticketmaster companies for various business purposes including developing and delivering targeted advertising on our websites and on websites of third parties, conducting general business analysis, and developing website content and services.

#### Changes to this Privacy Policy

We will occasionally update this Privacy Policy to reflect changes in our practices and services. When we post changes to this Privacy Policy, we will revise the "last updated" date at the top of this Privacy Policy.  If we make any material changes in the way we collect, use, and/or share your personal information, we will notify you by sending an e-mail to the e-mail address you most recently provided us in your account, profile or registration (unless we do not have such an email address), and/or by prominently posting notice of the changes on our website. We recommend that you check our website from time to time to inform yourself of any changes in this Privacy Policy or any of our other policies.  Regardless of any change to this Privacy Policy, your personal information will only be used and disclosed in the manner described in this Privacy Policy at the time your personal information was collected unless you otherwise consent.

#### How to contact us

If you have any questions about this Privacy Policy or our information-handling practices, or if you would like to access, update or correct your personal information, please contact us by e-mail or postal mail as follows:

Privacy Officer  
TicketWeb Canada  
Suite 3900  
1 Blue Jays Way  
Toronto, Ontario M5V 1J3  
416 345-9200 (0)
